Tonight's the night.
And it's going to happen
Again and again...
Has to happen.
Nice night.
Miami is a great town.
I love the cuban food.
Pork sandwiches...
My favorite.
But i'm hungry
For something different now.
There he is...
Mike donovan.
He's the one.
You're mine now.
So do exactly as i say.
What do you want?
I want you to be quiet.
Now drive.
Turn here.
Okay.
You have to listen...
And do what i say.
Look.
No.
Uh. yes.
No. no.
It's horrible. isn't it?
Isn't it?
Please.
Open your eyes
And look at what you did!
Look or i'll cut your eyelids
Right off your face.
It took me a long time
To get these little boys clean.
One of them had been
In the ground so long
He was falling apart.
I pulled him out
In bits and pieces.
Hail mary. full of grace.
The lord is...
Stop!
That never helped anybody.
Please.
You can have anything.
That's good. Beg.
Did these little boys beg?
I couldn't help myself.
I couldn't.
I just...
Please.
You have to understand.
Trust me.
I definitely understand.
See. i can't help myself.
Either.
Children...
I could never do that.
Not like you.
Never. ever kids.
Why?
I have standards.
Soon you'll be packed
Into a few
Neatly wrapped hefties
In my own small corner
Of the world.
It'll be a neater.
Happier place.
A better place.
My name is dexter.
Dexter morgan.
I don't know what made me
The way i am.
But whatever it was left
A hollow place inside.
People fake a lot
Of human interactions.
But i feel like
I fake them all.
And i fake them very well.
Ahoy!
Ahoy. there. captain!
Any big marlin out there today?
And that's my burden.
I guess.
But i don't blame
My foster parents for that.
Harry and doris morgan did
A wonderful job raising me.
But they're both dead now.
I didn't kill them...
Honest.
You're different.
Aren't you. dexter?
What do you mean. pop?
The billups say buddy
Disappeared.
I found the grave. son.
That dog was a noisy
Little creep. dad.
He was barking all night.
And mom couldn't sleep.
And she's very. very sick.
And that lousy dog
Was yapping
At every leaf that blew
Down the sidewalk.
There were a lot of bones
In there. dexter.
And not just buddy's.
Hola. dexter!
Blood...
Sometimes it sets my teeth
On edge.
Other times.
It helps me control the chaos.
The code of harry.
My foster father. is satisfied.
And so am i.
Harry was a great cop
Here in miami.
He taught me
How to think like one.
Taught me
How to cover my tracks.
I'm a very neat monster.
Dexter. are you there?
Okay. dex. please.
As soon as you get in.
I'm at a crime scene by the
Shithole the seven seas motel.
And i need you here.
Okay?
Dex? Please.
Pretty fucking please
With cheese on top.
That's my foul-mouthed
Foster sister. debra.
She has a big heart
But won't let anyone see it.
She's the only person
In the world who loves me.
I think that's nice.
I don't have feelings
About anything.
But if i could have feelings
At all. i'd have them for deb.
There's something strange
And disarming
About looking at a homicide
Scene in the daylight of miami.
It makes the most grotesque
Killings look staged.
Like you're in a new and daring
Section of disney world...
Dahmer land.
You better be a cop.
No. Forensics.
Dex!
Hey. what's up?
Jeez. deb. where the hell
Do you keep your gum?
They found another hooker
In the pool.
Another?
Chopped up
In bits and pieces.
That's the third one
In five months.
Third?
You mean there's a...
A serial killer.
That's right.
The other two
Were in broward.
Chopped up
Just like this one.
Any suspects?
Wish i knew.
I'm on vice. so laguerta
Sent me to my room
And told me to stay
Out of sight.
God forbid she listens
To what you have to say.
Tell me about it.
How does someone so dumb
Get so much power?
She knows
How to play the game.
You could take a lesson.
In what. ass-kissing?
Politics.
I just want to catch
This guy
Before he kills
Another one of my girls.
You can't get
So emotionally invested.
You always say that.
So did dad.
Yeah. but he also said.
"go after what you want."
I want out of vice
And into homicide.
What can i do to help?
You get these hunches.
You know.
With these types
Of murders.
Only sometimes.
Well. see if you get one
This time.
And can i bounce some ideas
Off of you later?
I always get smarter
When i'm talking to you.
You just need
A little more confidence.
All right. i'll take a look.
In the meantime. avoid laguerta
And talk to captain matthews.
He and dad were tight.
Maybe he'll put you on the case.
You're making me smarter
Already. see?
And keep the sex suit on
When you talk to the captain.
It'll help your cause.
That's a nice haircut.
Masuoka.
I saw your sister.
Damn. looking hot.
Yeah. she should.
It's hot as hell out here.
So...
Why are you here?
It's a crime scene.
Yeah.
But you do blood spatter.
So?
So...
There's no blood here.
What was that?
Yeah. There's no blood
In or on
Or near the body at all.
It's the weirdest thing
You ever saw.
Hey. angel.
Let's show him.
No blood.
No sticky. hot. messy.
Awful blood.
No blood at all.
Why hadn't i thought of that?
No blood.
What a beautiful idea.
How does the killer
Get rid of the blood?
It's hard to say.
The body's in good shape.
She got a nice ass. too.
Head is over there.
If you want to take a look.
This is unique.
No shit.
And no prints. either.
I've never seen such clean.
Dry. neat-looking dead flesh.
Wonderful.
Very clean.
Yeah.
But he didn't finish.
No terminó.
It looks pretty completo to me.
Angel.
No. no. Look.
He cut the leg in four pieces.
Almost like using a ruler.
But this leg
Is in three pieces.
Now. look. he started to make
A fourth cut but stopped.
It's possible
That he got interrupted.
Laguerta's looking
For a witness.
Working on the motel porter
Back there.
God help him.
No blood.
I can't think.
I have to get out of here.
Dex. ¿dónde va?
Where are you going?
Hey. no blood...
No trabajo.
I wish she'd stop that.
It's one of those
Mating rituals
Which i really don't
Understand.
But that bloodless body...
This guy may have exceeded
My own abilities.
Morning. dex.
Morning.
Hey. dex.
Hey. sue.
Dan.
How are the families?
Good. You?
See you
At the next bloodbath?
Never miss a party.
Thanks.
Salt of the earth.
These people.
And they work hard.
But with the solve rate
For murders at about 20%.
Miami is a great place for me.
A great place for me
To hone my craft.
Viva miami.
Dex.
Oh. i like your other outfit
Better.
You're a sick bastard.
Guess what.
Sex suit worked.
Captain put me on the case.
Laguerta wasn't happy.
But she needs to get laid.
I guess.
So congrats.
So you got any ideas yet?
Nope.
Well. uh. start working
On your mental autopsy
'Cause i could use
Your theories.
And thanks
For the fucking doughnut.
I got to go.
Doughnut?
You keeping
Your fingernails clean?
Never leave home
Without my rubber gloves.
Good boy.
So. anything new?
One of these days
You're gonna tell me.
I already told you.
Blood spatter doesn't take up
All my time.
I like doing it.
Maybe i can help out.
It fills my nights.
You have
A morbid sense of fun.
That's probably true.
You should find
A pretty girl.
I found you.
Charming
Like your father.
Just don't get me fired.
Then who would i
Bring doughnuts to?
Angel. ¿una más?
Gracias.
De nada.
Just like me...
Empty inside.
* cha. cha. cha *
Where the hell you been?
Crime scene.
What about these.
The hotel cokehead murders.
This dealer and the girl?
Oh.
Well.
This hallmark-looking couple
Didn't die by the hands
Of a professional.
No. this is child's play.
Messy work...
All that blood on the walls
Looks like a finger painting.
You give me the fucking creeps.
You know that. dexter?
Yeah. i know.
Sorry about that.
Fuck you.
Okay.
Is there something i can do?
You can give me a fucking
Analysis on the blood spatter.
You think i'm here to invite you
To my nephew's bris?
I didn't know
You were jewish.
Shut the fuck up
And write your report already.
Don't even know
Why i need you.
Grab a crayon. psycho.
And scribble this down.
Rival dealer came in.
Two scumbags slashed to hell.
Dealer stole the drugs.
Wham. bam. done.
And i don't give a shit
What you say
Because that's what happened
And that's who i'm looking for.
Hey. we are looking for
A motherfucking thief dealer.
You got it?
Okay. Sure.
I guess.
But i should get
Over there.
Then get over there already.
You fucking weirdo.
I need it quick.
I'm on it. sergeant.
The only real question i have
Is why. in a building
Full of cops.
All supposedly with a keen
Insight into the human soul.
Is doakes the only one
Who gets the creeps from me?
So this killer used
A sword?
Uh. no.
Probably a very sharp knife.
Look at the blood spatter.
Look at the patterns.
It tells a story.
You see this big pond of blood
Right there?
That's from the initial stab.
The male victim was standing
Right here.
And the killer plunged his knife
Into the shoulder.
Severing the carotid artery.
And... blpph!
Notice the long.
Thick. heavy drips?
Yeah. nice.
Now. over here. you have nice.
Clean sprays of blood.
That can only happen when
You're holding something light
And moving quick... nice. sharp
Slices through the body.
No splashes. no drips.
Clean and easy.
This guy knew
How to use a blade.
So we're looking
For a sushi chef.
Yeah.
Sushi chef is possible.
Wouldn't be my first choice.
But. hey. you never know.
Now what?
Now i eat.
The problem
With eating and driving.
Which i love to do.
Is not being able to employ
The 10:00-2:00 hand position
On the wheel.
It's a matter of public safety.
But there's always
A sacrifice.
This guy. jamie jaworski.
Six months ago. i think he fell
In love with a pretty brunette.
Mrs. Jane saunders...
A sweet mother of two married
To a successful banker...
All living a pleasant life
Until she.
Unfortunately. disappeared.
Leaving the kids
Emotionally devastated forever.
The cops arrested
My favorite valet.
But his lawyer got him off
On a faulty search warrant.
It's a good thing
I don't bother with them.
Animals don't like me.
Especially dogs.
I don't think they approve
Of what i sometimes do
To their masters.
That dog recognizes me
As easily
As i can recognize jaworski
Or any other killer.
Interesting taste
In literature.
His needs are evolving.
Turning violent.
He's on the fast track.
Harry: Have you ever wanted
To kill anything else?
You know. something bigger
Than a dog?
Yes.
Like a person?
Yeah.
But no one in particular.
Why didn't you?
I thought you and mom
Wouldn't like it.
Come here.
Friday night...
Date night in miami.
Every night
Is date night in miami.
And everyone's having sex.
But for me.
Sex never enters into it.
I don't understand sex.
Not that i have anything
Against women.
And i certainly
Have an appropriate
Sensibility about men.
But when it comes
To the actual act of sex.
It's always just seemed so...
Undignified.
But i have to play the game.
And after years
Of trying to look normal.
I think i met
The right woman for me.
Deb saved her life
On a domestic-dispute call.
Introduced us.
And we've been dating
For six months now.
She's perfect because rita is.
In her own way.
As damaged as me.
I'm running late.
I'll just be a sec.
I have to change.
Okeydoke.
Hi. dexter.
May i say that you look lovely
This evening?
Okay.
Master cody.
Handsome as ever.
High five.
Do the space shuttle.
Vanilla...
Chocolate.
And strawberry.
No coffee?
Which one do you think
Melts faster?
Ready?
Rita's ex-hubby.
The crack addict.
Repeatedly raped her.
Knocked her around.
Ever since then. she's been
Completely uninterested in sex.
That works for me.
Cody:
Will you be back?
Of course i'll be back.
I meant dexter.
You'll be asleep.
No. i won't.
Then i'll stop in
And we'll all play cards.
Texas hold 'em?
Give mommy a kiss.
Ready?
Yeah.
Needless to say.
I have some unusual habits.
Yet all these
Socially acceptable people
Can't wait to pick up hammers
And publicly smash their food
To bits.
Normal people
Are so hostile...
But not her.
Where are we going?
They might need me.
Just stay right there.
I'll be right back.
Son of a whore.
Who?
Talking about
This hijo de puta.
This asshole killer.
This maricón savage
Who makes us work
On a friday night.
Only mondays
Through thursdays...
That's what i always say.
Of course. coño.
Be reasonable.
Who wants to work
On a friday night?
I have my needs.
So. ¿cómo estás?
What are you doing here?
I was in the neighborhood.
I'm on a date.
A date?
Nice.
Same guy. same pattern.
Bone dry.
No blood again.
Pero mira esto.
There's some small differences
In the cuts this time.
Over here...
Rough. almost emotion.
Then over here.
Not so much.
And then over here...
Clean.
Muy bien.
Yeah. nice.
But look at this.
All bone.
The killer flayed the skin.
The flesh. completely off.
Now. why would he do that?
He's experimenting.
He's trying to find
The right way.
Is he experimenting
With the head. too?
What do you mean?
La bestia left her tits
And took her fucking head.
I don't find anyone
Around here.
And god only knows
What he's doing with it.
He's certainly
Raising the bar.
Damn.
This guy is good.
Will they catch him soon?
I doubt it.
The killer is an artist.
What do you mean?
His technique...
Is incredible.
I'm sorry.
I don't think i want to.
I mean.
I'm... i'm not ready.
Damn it. dexter.
What have i done now?
And why can't i get
That neat stack of body parts
Out of my head?
No blood.
Why did i touch her
That way?
I need to get back to my work.
Jaworski's website.
Scream-bitch-scream...
The mother of all rape sites.
That's it.
He's definitely the one.
Now it's just
A matter of time
Before he becomes
A drop of blood
In my glass-slide collection.
But i have to wait.
I have to be careful
And follow the code of harry.
Hey. dad.
I can explain.
You and i had
An understanding.
Whenever you get an urge.
You come to me. you tell me.
And we deal with it together.
I do tell you. dad.
The hell you do!
There's blood on this knife.
Animals.
I find animals. that's all.
Are you sure?
Are you telling me
The truth?
Yes.
I thought we had this
Under control.
You still don't remember
Anything from before.
You know.
Before we took you in?
No.
Is that why i have
These urges?
What happened changed something
Inside you.
It got into you too early.
I'm afraid your urge to kill
Is only gonna get stronger.
You're saying
I'll be like this forever.
You're a good kid. dex.
You are.
Otherwise. it would have been
A lot worse than animals.
Okay?
We can't stop this.
But maybe...
We can do something
To channel it.
Use it for good.
How could it ever be good?
Son. there are people out there
Who do really bad things.
Terrible people.
And the police
Can't catch them all.
Do you understand
What i'm saying?
You're saying
They deserve it.
That's right.
But. of course. you have to
Learn how to spot them.
How to cover your tracks.
But i can teach you.
Dad...
It's okay. dex.
You can't help
What happened to you.
But you can make
The best of it.
Remember this forever...
You are my son.
You are not alone.
And you are loved.
Okay.
Preparation is vital.
No detail can be overlooked.
And the ritual
Is intoxicating.
Duct tape...
Rubber sheets...
Necessary tools of the trade.
You can't bullshit me.
Dex.
Help me out.
Laguerta still has me
Interviewing hookers.
It's a waste of time.
Deb.
If he was interrupted...
Think.
Jesus christ. right.
Because then how do you have
Time to wrap all the pieces?
She's dumber
Than the boat people.
Throw her a fucking raft.
But now we have a fourth body.
And the cuts were different.
And that's telling us
A story.
The ritual is changing.
He's looking for some kind of
Inspiration and not finding it.
So he keeps doing it
Until he gets it right.
I could be wrong.
So how the hell was your date
With rita last night?
Great.
You should try it sometime.
You need a life.
Well.
Find me a guy i can trust.
I need a transfer to homicide.
Bro.
Then we'll see about a life.
It certainly
Would sound better
For the kids to say.
"mommy's on homicide."
Don't make me hit you.
Come on.
Then we could talk about
More little morgans.
Nephews and nieces.
You sound like mom.
I just... tell me what you know
About cell crystallization.
What do you mean?
I heard the coroner say it
Last night.
He was talking about
That dead...
The headless chick.
You got that look
In your eye.
I was there before you.
And i noticed this body looked
Different than the other ones.
The pieces were cold.
They were. like.
Meat-packing cold.
Is that what
Cell crystallization means?
My god.
Why didn't i think of that?
It's beautiful.
Dex.
What are you thinking?
Sorry.
That makes sense.
Cold.
It slows the flow of blood.
Why the hell
Is that important?
It's just a feeling.
That's not good enough.
I got to show laguerta
And her boys.
They're making fun of me.
They're saying
The only way i can close a case
Is on my back.
I got to get out of vice.
Dex. please. you got to...
Refrigerated truck.
What the fuck
Are you talking about?
A refrigerated truck.
He wants a cold environment
To slow the flow of blood.
Clean and mobile so he can dump
The garbage afterwards.
So i'm looking for
A refrigerated truck now?
Probably a stolen one.
You think there are a lot
Of stolen trucks out there?
Are you nuts?
In miami?
Choir... kids...
Just do something.
Just find my husband.
Ma'am. the detectives are
Looking into everything.
I'm pretty sure
I covered all my tracks.
What do you care
About that woman?
I don't.
I was just...
You like
When women cry?
You like that?
What's your thing.
Psycho?
I was just heading
To the briefing room.
You got no call to be in there.
So flee.
Lieutenant. this fucking guy
Doesn't belong.
I'm still waiting
For his spatter report
On the cokehead murders...
Go do that.
It's okay.
I don't want to upset anybody.
He can stay.
I'd like your input.
And we'll discuss your case
After the meeting.
How about we get started?
¯encontráste algo?
Nada todavía.
Hazme un favor
Y quítate la gorra.
Discúlpame.
You ready?
I'm gonna shame this bitch.
Just state your case
Clean and easy.
You'll be the hero.
Okay. settle down.
Now. has anyone tracked down
That witness?
Oh. come on. people.
Someone needs to find
Something here.
Uh. lieutenant laguerta?
Oh. officer morgan.
I didn't recognize you
With your clothes on.
I have an idea. something
In a different direction.
An idea?
Well. please.
Share it with us.
Cell crystallization.
Excuse me?
A little more confidence.
Please.
Um...
On the last victim.
I'd like to check and see
If any refrigerated trucks
Have been stolen
In the last... week or so.
Refrigerated trucks
Like ice-cream trucks?
Um...
No. not ice-cream trucks.
A refrigerated vehicle
That could cause
That kind of tissue damage.
A refrigerated truck
That's mobile
So he'll be harder to catch.
A refrigerated truck
That might give us a lead.
That's very interesting.
Very creative.
Let's keep looking
For the witness. okay?
We know that he or she
Is out there.
The forensic evidence.
The interrupted cut proves
That there was an eyewitness.
Now. somebody out there
Saw something.
So let's concentrate
On finding that person. okay?
But...
Just keep talking
To all your hookers.
That's all for today.
What the fuck
Was i supposed to say?
The only reason
I'm in here
Is because the captain said
They had to let me in.
But he didn't say
They had to listen to you.
Well. right again.
So say adiós to my career.
I'm gonna die a meter maid.
Stop it.
Deb. there's another way.
Find the truck.
Excuse me. dexter...
My office. please.
What the hell?
What the fuck?
Are you boning her?
No.
Oh. my god!
Deb. wait.
Shut up.
It had nothing to do
With drugs.
L.t.. this is a waste
Of our damn time.
I think sergeant doakes
Is right.
I read the other reports. all
The other forensic analysis.
Everyone agrees
The cokehead murders
Had nothing to do
With cocaine.
It was a crime of passion.
The murderer came to kill
The woman. not the dealer.
He did him quick
And got him out of the way.
But he sure as hell took his
Sweet time slicing up that lady.
And you don't do that
Unless you have a close.
Personal relationship
With someone.
Probably an ex-boyfriend.
That's who i'd look for.
Okay.
It's a bit of a push.
But. sergeant.
You should check it out.
I'm watching you.
Motherfucker.
Jaworski's been
Coming here for weeks...
Likes to steal
All the copper plumbing.
There's good money in that.
No security guards...
That's good.
Fuck!
Talk.
What do you mean?
I think you know
What i mean.
No.
Oh. god.
Talk to me
About jane saunders.
Okay.
I did her.
How?
In a movie...
Snuff film.
But i'm not sorry.
Of course not.
No. i'm not sorry. either.
Hello?
Hey. I'm...
i'm sorry.
I mean. i'm sorry
About the other night.
But. uh... look. dex.
I really.
Really need to see you.
So can you...
Can you come by later.
You know. just for.
Like. a little while?
I mean. i'm really...
All right.
What are you doing now?
I'm just finishing up
A little project.
But i'll come by later.
Okay. bye.
All in all.
It was a good night.
One less amateur filmmaker
Polluting the internet.
No way.
Give us a minute.
Hanging in there?
This will teach me
To tailgate.
Let's go over this again.
I'm all yours.
So all the ice trucks
In miami...
Bit of a coincidence.
Don't you think?
Sure. during business hours.
But this time of night.
A truck like that sticks out.
And you followed it.
That's right.
You never saw the driver?
Just high beams
And a flying head.
So then he must have already had
The head with him
In the front seat.
That's weird.
Why would he keep it there?
I don't know. so he could use
A carpool lane?
It just seems odd.
Your sister has
This ice-truck theory.
And then here you are
To back it up.
She's good. lieutenant.
You should give her a chance.
You know.
You should call me maria.
But i'll tell you who's good...
You are.
Doakes picked up the killer
In the cokehead murders.
You were right.
It was her boyfriend.
Of course.
Doakes still hates you.
Tell me. dexter.
How did you get
To be so smart. huh?
Mm...
Lots of sleep.
Is it okay if i fill out
That report tomorrow?
Sure thing.
You're tired.
Good night. lieutenant.
I'll catch you later.
Dex.
It's been a while.
I'm sorry.
I was worried.
I didn't know what to do.
I called in sick.
I mean...
Are you okay?
Yeah. i'm fine.
I was just...
I'm sorry.
There was another... you know.
Oh.
Well. the kids slept over
Next door.
Okay.
Would you like to come in?
I don't want to lose you.
Dex.
Okay. sure.
And...
Well... i want you.
I mean...
Oh.
Okay.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Do you mind?
Um. no.
It could be the kids.
Better get it. then.
Hello?
Cody.
Cody. stop crying.
Sweetie.
All right.
I'll come get you.
Cody just threw up
All over colleen's couch.
I got to go get him.
Tell me we're okay.
Better than.
Okay.
Go be a good mom.
Okay. that was close.
I'll admit. making out
With rita was...
Interesting.
But if i don't keep a lid
On this.
It could be the end of us.
I suppose i should be upset.
Even feel violated.
But i'm not.
No.
In fact. i think this is
A friendly message.
Kind of like.
"hey. want to play?"
And. yes. i want to play.
I really. really do.
* oye. cayuco *
* oye. mi cha. cha. cha *
* pero mira.
Baila. baila cayuquito *
* como tú goza
Mi cha. cha. cha *